(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-01T00:51:57.088299",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
じょーじょーゆーじょー まじまじかーちょー
Splendid friendship, everything's going great!
はいっ ちゃいましょう！
Come on, let's go!
キミは Best Best Friend!
You are my best, best friend!
ちょっとふざけてみたら もっとふざけて返してくる
When I try messing around, you mess right back!
居心地いいったらありゃしない！
It's the most comfortable feeling ever!
いやなことあったって そっこー忘れちゃうんだ いつだって
Whenever something bad happens, I forget it right away!
じゃんじゃんやりましょー！
Let's keep going on and on!
なんのよ やばいシンクロ感！
What is this insane synchronization?!
いつも大騒ぎ かなりご近所迷惑
Always making a huge racket, a nuisance to neighbors.
今何時？ えっとね、ヨロレイヒー わけわかんないない！！
What time is it? Uh, yoroleihi~ Makes no sense!
ソーレド・シラー 想像以上！ なんていうか最高！
So-re-do-shi-ra- Beyond imagination! The best!
あだこだ言ってても友達わっしょい！
No matter what we bicker about, friends rule!
じょーじょーゆーじょー まじまじかーちょー
Splendid friendship, everything's going great!
（はいっ ちゃいましょう！ キミは Best Best Friend!）
(Come on, let's go! You are my best, best friend!)
24時間一緒でも問題ない！
Even being together 24 hours is no problem!
まるで双子か親子かクローン細胞ー
Like twins, parent-child, or clone cells—
これじゃ恋愛する必要とかなくなくない？
Doesn't this mean we don't need romance?
それとこれとは全く全く別問題！！
That and this are totally different issues!!
ケンカしちゃったときも かなり凹んだときも
Even when we fight or get really down,
ひとりでにいたいよなときも ふと気づけば近くにいる
or want to be alone, we're right next to each other!
しなばもろとも
Going down together!
なんでだろそばにいたいんだ
I wonder why, I want to be by your side.
キミと一緒なら時計100倍速！
When I'm with you, time moves 100 times faster!
楽しいな 楽しすぎるんだ さすが最強Friend!
It's so fun, way too fun! The ultimate friend!
なんのよ やばいシンクロ感！
What is this insane synchronization?!
いつも大騒ぎ かなりご近所迷惑 今何時？
Always making a huge racket, a nuisance. What time is it?
えっとね、ヨロレイヒー わけわかんないない！！
Uh, yoroleihi~ Makes no sense!
ソーレド・シラー 想像以上！
So-re-do-shi-ra- Beyond imagination!
なんていうか最高！ 友達わっしょい！
The best! Friends rule!
じょーじょーゆーじょー まじまじかーちょー
Splendid friendship, everything's going great!
（はいっ ちゃいましょう！ キミは Best Best Friend!）
(Come on, let's go! You are my best, best friend!)
おかころのじょーじょーゆーじょー2番をお聴きください
Please listen to Okakoro's 'Joujou Yuujou' part 2!
おんなじテレビ観てて メールで実況中継
Watching the same TV show, live commentary via email,
CM入れば電話タイム！
phone time during commercials!
遠くにいるときでも 近くに感じてるんだ
Even when far apart, I feel you close by.
よろしく！ ガンガンいきましょー！
Let's get along! Push forward full throttle!
やばい！ 弁当忘れた カンパして！！
Oh no! I forgot my lunch, spot me food!!
やだよ命の源 焼きそばパン
No way, yakisoba bread is life!
ちょっと友達なんでしょ ゴムみたいな
Aren't we friends? You're like rubber—
それとこれとは全く全く別問題！！
That and this are totally different issues!!
変な気は使わない 顔色なんか知らない
No ceremony, no caring about moods,
でも傷つけたりしない 神様マジありがと！
but we never hurt each other. Thanks, God!
できたマブダチ （やったー！ おっしゃー！）
We made true best friends! (Yay! Alright!)
最高超 腹筋崩壊 涙が出るくらい笑い疲れちゃうんだ
Abs collapsing, laughing until in tears!
何しようか？ 何をしましょうか？ しりとりレッツゴー！
What shall we do? Shiritori, let's go!
「南無阿弥陀」 「だ」でしょ？ 「壇ノ浦」
''Namu Amida'...' 'Da'? 'Dannoura'—
ララ 「ラブゴリラ！」 なんだその生きもの？！
Lara 'Love Gorilla!' What creature is that?!
もう飽きた！ マジか！？ ヨロレイヒー 意味はないないない！！！
Bored! Seriously?! Yoroleihi~ No meaning at all!
そう友達とか ずっと厚苦しく思ってた
I always thought friends were so stifling,
でもでも…やっぱ言えないや ビコーズ！！
but... I can't say it. Because!!
なんのよ やばいシンクロ感！ いつも大騒ぎ
What is this insane synchronization?! Always noisy,
かなりご近所迷惑 今何時？ えっとね、ヨロレイヒー
quite a nuisance. What time is it? Yoroleihi~
ソーレド・シラー 想像以上！ なんていうか最高！
So-re-do-shi-ra- Beyond imagination! The best!
あだこだ言ってても友達わっしょい！ じょーじょーゆーじょー
Bicker all we want, friends rule! Splendid friendship,
まじまじかーちょー （はいっ ちゃいましょう！ キミは Best Best Friend!）
everything's great! (Come on, let's go! You are my best, best friend!)
なんでだろそばにいたいんだ キミと一緒なら時計100倍速！
I want to be by your side. Time moves 100x faster!
楽しいな 楽しすぎるんだ さすが最強Friend!
So fun, way too fun! The ultimate friend!
なんのよ やばいシンクロ感！ いつも大騒ぎ
What is this insane synchronization?! Always noisy,
かなりご近所迷惑 今何時？ えっとね、ヨロレイヒー
a nuisance. What time is it? Yoroleihi~
ソーレド・シラー 想像以上！ なんていうか最高！
So-re-do-shi-ra- Beyond imagination! The best!
あだこだ言ってても友達わっしょい！ じょーじょーゆーじょー
Bicker all we want, friends rule! Splendid friendship,
まじまじかーちょー （はいっ ちゃいましょう！ キミは Best Best Friend!）
everything's great! (Come on, let's go! You are my best, best friend!)
なんのよ やばいシンクロ感！ いつも大騒ぎ
What is this insane synchronization?! Always noisy,
かなりご近所迷惑 今何時？ えっとね、ヨロレイヒー
a nuisance. What time is it? Yoroleihi~
ソーレド・シラー 想像以上！ なんていうか最高！
So-re-do-shi-ra- Beyond imagination! The best!
あだこだ言ってても友達わっしょい！ じょーじょーゆーじょー
Bicker all we want, friends rule! Splendid friendship,
まじまじかーちょー （はいっ ちゃいましょう！ キミは Best Best Friend!）
everything's great! (Come on, let's go! You are my best, best friend!)
なんでだろそばにいたいんだ キミと一緒なら時計100倍速！
I want to be by your side. Time moves 100x faster!
楽しいな 楽しすぎるんだ さすが最強Friend!
So fun, way too fun! The ultimate friend!
なんのよ やばいシンクロ感！ いつも大騒ぎ
What is this insane synchronization?! Always noisy,
かなりご近所迷惑 今何時？ えっとね、ヨロレイヒー
a nuisance. What time is it? Yoroleihi~
ソーレド・シラー 想像以上！ なんていうか最高！
So-re-do-shi-ra- Beyond imagination! The best!
あだこだ言ってても友達わっしょい！ チャラチャラチャラチャチャーン
Bicker all we want, friends rule! Chara chara chara chacha-n!
みんな〜！おかころが来たぞー！
Everyone~! Okakoro is here!
きちゃったぞー！
We're here!
きちゃった、きちゃった、きちゃったぞー！
We made it, we made it, we're here!
みんな見えてるよ、ありがとう！
We can see everyone, thank you!
なんか緊張…緊張…緊張…緊張だけじゃねえね。
I'm so nervous... nervous...
not just nervous, though.
あらためまして、このライブゲーマーズの猫猫おかゆと…
Once again, I'm Nekomata Okayu
of Hololive Gamers...
犬神ころねと申します！
and I'm Inugami Korone!
わぁーーい！
Yay~~!
今日はね、おかころ2周年の3Dライブにきてくださって…
Today, thank you so much for coming
to Okakoro's 2nd anniversary 3D live...
べっ…べっ…だいぶかんだ！
V-very... I stumbled so much!
皆さんに…ありがとうございます！
Thank you... thank you everyone!
どうだった？1曲目。
How was it? The first song.
いや、なんかね、お尻をねぶつけてね飛んでく…
Well, you know, bumping our butts
and flying off...
ころねがね…
Korone was...
あのリハの時より飛んだなと思って。
I thought she flew further
than during rehearsal.
そうだな、やっぱり飛んでたね。
That's right, she definitely flew.
爆発してたじゃん。
She was totally exploding!
そこがね、うちはねすごいちょっと良かったなってね。
I thought that part was
really great for us.
最後みんな気づいてちょっとね、おかゆにチューしたんだよ、気づいた？
At the end, did you notice I gave
Okayu a little kiss?
そうだよ！
That's right!
気づいた？
Did you notice?
気づいてない人のほうが多いかもしれない。
More people probably
didn't notice.
チューってしてたんだよね。
She went in for a kiss.
そう。ということで…
Yeah. And so...
どうせっきゅう？
How was 'Thank You'?
ということで、本日はこちらのハッシュタグ「おかころ2周年3Dライブ」でたくさんつぶやいてくれて、嬉しいあとでね。
So, today, please tweet a lot with
the hashtag #Okakoro2ndAnniversary...
嬉しいあとでね、おかゆと2人でね、そう、見ますからね。
Okayu and I will check them
together later, you know.
ゼロゼロゼロゼロ…いっぱい見ますからよろしくお願いします。
Zero zero zero zero...
we'll look at tons of them.
あの、「上々友情」は1周年のときに2人でね、また歌いたいねって、今回絶対歌いたいと思ってね。
As for 'Joujou Yuujou', we wanted
to sing it together again since our 1st...
一番最初にね、持ってきた！歌いたかったんで。
We brought it as the very first song!
Because we wanted to sing it.
歌えたんでね、ちょっと、わちゃわちゃしちゃった。
We were able to sing it,
so we got a little rambunctious.
そう、おにぎりゃとコロネスキーが、なんと駆けつけてくれてるってみんなに聞いたんだけど。
Also, I heard that the Onigirya
and Koronesky rushed over to support us.
あ、みんな！
Ah, everyone!
めっちゃいるじゃん！最前列取れよ！
There are so many of you!
Get the front row!
そんな、そんな控えめなんだよ。最前列でがんばれよみんな。
Why are you so reserved?
Do your best in the front row.
しかもなんかコロネスキーはペンライト持ってないのかな、これは？
And it looks like Koronesky
doesn't have penlights, is that right?
あ、なんか何？コロネスキーちょっとアップをお願いしていいですか？
Wait, what? Koronesky,
can we get a close-up, please?
何持ってんのそれ？
What are you holding there?
なんだこれわ？
What is this?
あ、指が光ってますね！
Ah, their fingers are glowing!
なるほどね、2周年を迎えたコロネスキーは指が光るようになってるんだね。すげえ！進化だね。
I see, Koronesky celebrating their 2nd
anniversary have glowing fingers. Amazing!
皆さん、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
皆さんありがとう来てくれて。
Thank you for coming, everyone.
でね、この通常衣装なんだけど、今日はもうアイドル衣装にね、着替えちゃおうかなって思ってるから…
And you know, as for these regular outfits,
since we're changing into our idol outfits...
これをちょっと見納めだから、ちょっとこれでちょっと1回スクショしてもらう？ちょっと。
This will be the last time seeing them,
so could you take a screenshot?
ちょっとだけ、ちょっとだけスクショしてもらう？
Could you take just a little,
just a little screenshot?
おかころがね、この通常衣装でさ並んでるのも珍しいし…
It's rare for Okakoro to stand
side-by-side in these regular outfits...
待って、待って、レアだよみんな。レア、分かってる？これレアだからね！
Wait, wait, it's rare, everyone.
It's rare, do you know? This is rare!
しっぽ、しっぽ見せる。しっぽ見る。
Show your tails. Let's look at the tails.
ころさんのしっぽ。おかゆと並ぶと本当にボサボサだね。
Korone's tail. Compared to Okayu's,
it's really fluffy and messy.
でもそれがね、いいんだよ。いい、本当。
But that's what's good about it.
Really good.
撮れた？みんな撮れた？
Did you get it? Did everyone get it?
撮ったってね。
They took it.
撮れたかな。動きすぎ、1回止まるか。
Did they get it? You're moving too much,
let's pause for a moment.
ということでね、この後は着替えるんですけれども。
And so, after this,
we'll be changing clothes.
なんと、なんと！次の曲は…
Guess what! The next song is...
「スキスキ曲」！
'Suki Suki Song'!
大丈夫？いける？
Are you okay? Can you do it?
できない！できない！
We can't! We can't!
じゃあ今日はこれで終わりにしたいと思います。みんなありがとうございました！バイバーイ！
Well then, we'll end it here for today.
Thank you everyone! Bye-bye!
ってて
Ouch...
よかよか
All right, all right.
次に行った曲をみんな想像してみてください
Everyone, try guessing what song comes next.
こーねからは言いません
Korone won't tell you.
準備できた？
Are you ready?
オッケー！オッケー！
Okay! Okay!
じゃあ次の曲いってみよう！
Then let's go to the next song!
揺れる街灯 穿つ雨
The shaking street lights, the pelting rain,
揺れる感情 感覚のテレパス
My wavering feelings, an emotional telepath,
迷子のふたりはコンタクト
The lost two make contact,
ココロは恋を知りました
And my heart learned of love.
タイトロープ ツギハギの制服
Tightrope, a patchwork uniform,
重力のディスコミュニケーション
A severe discommunication,
眼光 赤色にキラキラ
A glint in my eyes, twinkling red,
ナニかが起きる胸騒ぎ
It feels like something's gonna happen; a premonition.
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I'm an alien,
あなたの心を惑わせる
Leading astray your heart,
交ざり合う宇宙の引力で
With the melding gravity of the universe,
感じてる気持ちはトキメキ
The feeling I felt; my throbbing heart.
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, that's right, I'm your alien,
引き合う心は逃げられない
Your heart pulling against mine can't run away,
あなたに未体験あげる
I'll give you an un-experience,
異世界の果てまで トキメキ スキ
Till the end of the other-world, heart throbbing, love.
点灯と消灯を繰り返している蛍光灯
A fluorescent light repeatedly switching off and on,
超常な混沌が静かにあなたを蝕んだ
The paranormal confusion quietly ate into you,
並行な信号は特異点に交わり交わった
The parallel signals intersected due to singular point,
創造現実盲信症 感応性本能
Created-reality-blind-acceptance, sensitivity instinct
シンドローム ひとりきり夜な夜な
Syndrome, in solitude, each night behind bars,
空想 描くまるですぐリモワさ
A daydream turns it to a grimoire,
サーチライト 避ける浮遊機
Mystery drone, a bright light shone, avoid the radar,
「まだあなたはすべてを知りたい?」
"Do you truly want me to tell you everything?"
エイリアン わたしエイリアン
Alien, I'm an alien,
あなたの心を 惑わせる
Leading astray your heart,
瞳に映らない引力に
Staring into a pair of eyes gravity escaped,
気づいてよ わたしは――
Today you'll see what I am really...
エイリアン あなたのエイリアン
Alien, that's right, I'm your alien,
触れ合えば傷は二度と消えない
Keep touching that wound and it's doomed to turn into a scar,
降り注ぐ無数の隕石も
'Cause every meteor that hits the earth leaves a mark,
ときめく心には届かない!
Disaster looming past the blue sky keeps me alive!
エイリアン ふたりはエイリアン
Alien, the two of us aliens,
高鳴る気持ちが抑えられない!
This pounding feeling between us still unidentified,
あなたは未確認生命体
A wonder to the universe, you and i,
異世界の果てまであなたが好き
Supernatural yet natural / How I'll always love you
おかゆお疲れ様ー！
Okayu, great job!
お疲れ様！
Good job!
あのさ、1つ聞きたいんだけどね
Say, there's one thing I want to ask.
最後のキスの嘆きキスは誰に送ったキスなの？
Whose kiss was that sighing kiss at the end sent to?
世界中のみんなになだよ
To everyone in the world!
え、こねには？
Eh, what about Kone?
今いただきましたので
Since I just received it now—
ころさんにしか見えてない中継だよ
It's a broadcast only visible to Koro-san!
ありがとう、もう一回もう一回！
Thank you, one more time, one more time!
いただきましたので大丈夫です
I received it, so it's fine.
え、可愛かったね、おかゆね
Eh, it was cute, Okayu.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ころねも着替えたらどう？
Why don't you change too, Korone?
かわいい！ありがとう、着替えました！
Cute! Thanks, I changed!
おかゆ、今の曲どうだった？なんか踊って歌ってみてどうだった？
Okayu, how was that song? How was it singing and dancing to it?
いや、エイリアンエイリアンはね、すごい好きな曲で
Well, Alien Alien is a song I really like.
普通になんか普段からさ、お掃除しながら歌ったりしてるけど
Usually I sing it while cleaning up and stuff,
やっぱみんなの前で歌うと、やっぱちょっとね緊張した
but singing it in front of everyone made me a bit nervous.
緊張したよね、でも可愛かったよ！
You were nervous, but it was cute!
でも上手にできた！上手にできたね、本当に！
But you did a great job! You really did a great job!
え、次の曲もおかゆの
Eh, the next song is also Okayu's...
次の曲も歌うので、あの連続でね、あの聞いていただけるとうれしいです。
Since I'll be singing the next song too, I'd be happy if you'd listen to them back-to-back.
では、次のお歌のじゃあ、ここ見てほしいポイントとかあれば。
Well, as for the next song, if there are any highlights you want people to notice—
ええとね、次は次も尻尾を可愛く揺らすので、僕の尻尾をいっぱい見てほしいです。
Um, next, my tail will be swaying cutely too, so I want you to watch my tail a lot.
いいね。
Nice.
じゃあ、ココネも見てるからね。
Well, Kokone's watching too.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
がんばれ！
Do your best!
いや、ココネも準備してくるぞ。
Yeah, Kokone's getting ready too.
じゃあ2曲続けて、どうぞ！
Now, continuing with two songs, here we go!
キラキラ光る 流星群
A shimmering meteor shower
わたし想うわ ウォアイニー
I think to myself "wo ai ni"
星のままに 逃避行
An escape among the stars
ああ、そんなストーリーも悪くないのさ
Ah, a story like that isn't too bad
ネオンの街から プレビュー
A preview from the neon town
月世界まで ウォンビーロング
To the moon world "won't be long"
あの星の名も 忘れたの
I've even forgotten the name of that star
満ち月の 飛行
Flight of the full moon
彗星ハネムーン
Comet Honeymoon
あなたとランデヴー
Rendezvous with you
恋しているのさ ふたり
The two of us are in love
愛してモナムール
Love me, mon amour
いっそ ふたりきり
Or rather, just the two of us
どこか遠くへ いこうか
Shall we go somewhere far away?
曖昧な エアライン
A vague airline
言葉は いらない
No words needed
やっと出逢えた あなたと
With you whom I've finally met
星巡り 繰り返し
Repeating planetary tours
目指すは 宇宙の終着点さ
Aiming for the ultimate destination of the universe
アハハーン アハハーン あははん
Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-han
アハハーン アハハーン うおうお
Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-harn Woo-ooo
小天体の ライナー
Liner of a minor body
その数回転の あいだ
During those few rotations
運命星も 越えた
Surpassing even the planet of destiny
愛の瞬きが プレイバック
The blinking of love is a playback
環状線結んだ
Connected by a loop line
あなたは 終端ライダー
You are the terminal rider
ロマンス飛行を 今
Now, a romantic flight
動かない信号の 赤色
The red color of the immobile traffic light
月世界まで ウォンビーロング
To the moon world "won't be long"
モスクワの海が 旅の終わり
The Sea of Moscow is the end of the journey
そこで お別れさ
We will part ways there
彗星ハネムーン
Comet Honeymoon
あなたとランデヴー
Rendezvous with you
恋しているのさ ふたり
The two of us are in love
愛してモナムール
Love me, mon amour
由縁なくって いいよ
Even if there's no particular reason
遠くへいこうか
Shall we go far away?
彗星ハネムーン
Comet Honeymoon
果てまでランデヴー
Rendezvous to the very end
そうさ今だけは ふたり
Yes, just for the now, the two of us
ねえきいて モナムール
Hey, listen, mon amour
片道切符でも いいでしょ?
Is a one-way ticket okay?
夜が明けたら 何処へいこうか?
Where shall we go when night breaks?
永久に出逢えぬ あなたと
With you whom I'll never meet again eternally
星巡り 繰り返し
Repeating planetary tours
目指すは夢の 出発点さ
Aiming for the starting point of dreams
アハハーン アハハーン あははん
Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-han
アハハーン アハハーン うおうお
Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-harn Woo-ooo
彗星ハネムーン
Comet Honeymoon
果てまでランデヴー
Rendezvous to the very end
そうさ今だけは ふたり
Yes, just for the now, the two of us
ねえきいて モナムール
Hey, listen, mon amour
片道切符でもいいでしょ?
Is a one-way ticket okay?
夜が明けたら 何処へいこうか?
Where shall we go when night breaks?
永久に出逢えぬ あなたと
With you whom I'll never meet again eternally
星巡り 繰り返し
Repeating planetary tours
目指すは夢の 出発点さ
Aiming for the starting point of dreams
アハハーン アハハーン あははん
Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-han
アハハーン アハハーン うおうお
Ah-ha-harn Ah-ha-harn Woo-ooo
彗星ハネムーン
Comet Honeymoon
果てまでランデヴー
Rendezvous to the very end
そうさ今だけは ふたり
Yes, just for the now, the two of us
ねえきいて モナムール
Hey, listen, mon amour
おねだりしてみてほしいの ダーリン
I want you to pester me, darling
あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
You don't listen to what I say at all
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
I've told you so much to stop smoking and drinking
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かせず
Everyday two packs and seven cans without fail
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Even if your liver is damaged and grows defective
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to pester me,
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to what I say at all!
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
I've told you so much to stop smoking and drinking,
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
two packs and seven cans every single day without fail.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても 看病してあげないんだから
Even if your liver gives out, I won't nurse you!
ああ言うこう言う って言っても聞かない
You have a comeback for every remark and won't budge.
あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart is pitch black.
さしてほしい感じで
With a feeling like you want me to pierce through,
わざと口にしないの ズルくない？
you purposely keep quiet. Isn't that unfair?
ばっかじゃないの
How ridiculous!
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen. What I want is a shapeless thing.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ
I won't make fun of you. Look and listen, peek deep
瞳の奥の方 真っ直ぐ見つめて
into my eyes, and gaze straight ahead.
おねだりしてみてほしいの
Do you want me to pester you?
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷり
I gazed at you so devotedly, yet now you pretend not to know.
っていうか それって胡坐かいてるだけなんじゃないですかぶっちぎり
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels? Hands down!
舌先三寸 あなたのお陰で私のハートはボロボロです
Thanks to your smooth talk, my heart is all worn out.
ねえ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない？ そうじゃない？
Hey, isn't this somewhat stupid? Isn't that right?
どこか足元見てる感じで 舐め回されてる感じで
Feeling like you're looking down on me, feeling like I'm being appraised.
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃなくない？ そうよ面倒くさいこと
Is this not tactics and winning or losing? You make everything so annoying,
してるから面倒くさいことになるんだよ
so naturally it turns into a huge hassle!
堪忍してダーリンねえ聞いて 切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Please have mercy, darling, listen. Pain isn't a mere decoration.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで 触ってよ 心の奥の方
Don't look away, don't run away. Touch deep inside my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない おねだりしてはくれないの？
This isn't a momentary thing. Won't you pester me back?
言葉に出来ない怯えさは 強さではないのよ
The cowardice you can't put into words isn't true strength.
甘えてないで口に出してよ
Don't just act spoiled, say it out loud!
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen. What I want is a shapeless thing.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you. Look and listen, peek deep into my eyes.
堪忍してねてないで 甘えてよ 私の素顔を
Please have mercy, don't sleep on me, and adore my true self!
お願いダーリン そばにいて 触らせて 心の奥の方
Please, darling, stay by my side and let me touch deep inside your heart.
真っ直ぐ見つめて おねだりしてみてほしいの
Gaze straight ahead. I want you to pester me.
わあー！
Whoa!
お、お疲れ様！
Gr-great job!
心臓いっちゃった！
My heart almost stopped!
最後ここじゃなくて大丈夫、大丈夫 ちょっと
Are you okay? At the end there—wait, are you alright?
よろけじょ、よろけでした？まってよ大丈夫だよね？バレてない？
Did you stumble? Wait, is it okay? Did anyone notice?
バレてない？
Did they notice?
バレてない！よ、見てなかったから！ほんとのとこ、奇跡的に見てなかった！
They didn't notice! I wasn't looking! Honestly, I miraculously missed it!
本当に？
Really?
いや、めちゃすごかった、ダンス！
No, the dancing was amazing!
いやもう最後ね、もう全部吹き飛んだんだけど。
I mean, at the very end, everything just blew away from my mind!
いやでもころさんね、ずっとね、このダンス練習してたから。
But Korone-san, you know, you've been practicing this dance for so long.
めっちゃしてた！
I really was!
そう、でも最後転んじゃっただけであとはもう完璧だったじゃん。
Right, but other than tripping at the end, it was totally perfect, right?
ね？
Right?
はい。
Yes.
でもみんなさ、すごいコメントでもね
But everyone in the chat was saying—
本当？
Really?
すごいなんか、「あつが気持ちいい」みたいな、「可愛い、可愛い」ってねみんな言ってたよ。
Everyone was saying things like "So passionate!" and "So cute!"
え本当？
Oh really?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おかゆも見てくれてありがとう！
Thanks for watching too, Okayu!
応援してた、ばっちり。やばい。ばっちり応援してた。
I was cheering you on, totally! I was rooting for you so hard.
いや、今度はころばないようにしなきゃ。
Well, next time I shouldn't trip!
え、次のさ、曲はさ、その、何をさ、注目してみたらいいの？
Hey, what should we look out for in the next song?
次の曲は結構、えっとね、なんかけんぽ、早いというか、ノリノリの曲だから、ちょっとそれに合わせてころちゃんが頑張って動いてるところをね、うんうんうん、見てほしいけど、また転ぶかもしれないから、そこに注目してください。
The next song is pretty fast-paced and upbeat, so I want you to watch Korone-chan working hard to move along with it... but she might trip again, so please keep an eye out for that!
だってよみんな！ころさんがね、もしかしたら転ぶかもしれないけど、転ばないかもしれないっていうのを、楽しんでね、楽しんでください。
There you have it, everyone! Korone-san might or might not trip, so please enjoy watching and see what happens!
見ていけたらなって思いますね。
I hope you all enjoy watching.
はい！
Yes!
ころさん大丈夫？ちょっと、あの、休憩する？お水飲んで、お水。
Korone-san, are you okay? Do you want to take a break? Drink some water.
いやマジでおかゆのね、あの頑張ってころさんっていうね、あの可愛いポーズとね、きみがもらえたらこんな頑張れるから。
Seriously, getting that cute pose and hearing "Do your best, Korone-san" from Okayu gives me so much energy!
あ、でもさっきのね、おねがいダーリンみたいに、
Ah, but just like that "Onegai Darling" earlier—
あ、ちょっと私も振り向いてやろうかな？
Oh, should I turn around and do it too?
いいねいいね！じゃあ、おねがいしていいですか？
That's great! Then, may I ask you for a favor?
はい！
Yes!
じゃあ振り向いて、こっから。
Then turn around from here.
ころさん、がんばって！
Korone-san, do your best!
がんばるー！
I'll do my best!
いって見よ！というわけで
Let's go check it out! So,
では、ころさんの次の曲、どうぞ！
here is Korone-san's next song, go ahead!
ダメダメよ
Don't you dare!
右から左へと言葉が流れる
Words flow across the screen from right to left,
退屈そうな顔 画面見つめる君
and you look like you're bored, staring at the screen.
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
右から左へと言葉が流れる
Words flow across the screen from right to left,
退屈そうな顔 画面見つめる君
and you look like you're bored, staring at the screen.
次元の壁越えていつでも逢いに行く
Cross the dimensional wall and come see me anytime,
心の内準備をちゃんとしておいてね
Make sure you prepare your heart properly.
君のこと誰よりも分かっている
I know you better than anyone else,
だから私に任せて
so leave it to me!
怖がらないで二人で踊りましょう
Don't be scared, let's dance together!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
弾けるリズムに合わせて
Dance along to the popping rhythm,
嫌なこと何もかも全部忘れて
Forget all the bad things and everything else!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
私はここに居るから
I'll be right here,
少しでも視線を逸らしちゃ
so don't look away even for a second!
ダメダメよ
Don't you dare!
重くて見れない日
Days when it's too heavy to see,
兄貴に釣られた日
Days when you're teased by your older brother,
心で呼んでみて
Just call for me from your heart,
すぐに飛んでゆくわ
and I'll fly to you right away!
授業では教わらないことを
I'll teach you things they don't teach you in class,
君に教えてあげるわ夜の扉を二人で開きましょう
Let's open the night's door together!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
あふれる想いはFor you
Overflowing feelings are for you,
限りあるこの時を胸に刻んで
Carrying this limited time in our hearts.
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
朝日が昇ればサヨナラ
Saying goodbye when the morning sun rises,
寂しそうなそんな目されても
Even if you give me that lonely look,
ダメだから
Don't you dare!
君のこと誰よりも分かっている
I know you better than anyone else,
だから全てを晒して
So let's expose everything,
生まれた意味を二人で見つけましょう
And find the meaning of our birth together!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
高まる鼓動を感じて
Feel the rising heartbeat,
さあ覚悟できたらこの手を取って
Once you're ready, take my hand!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
輝く君が好きなの
You love the shining you,
全力で飛び出そう
Let's jump out with all our might,
用意はいいかしら
Are you ready?
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
弾けるリズムに合わせて
Dance along to the popping rhythm,
嫌なこと何もかも全部忘れて
Forget all the bad things and everything else!
ルカルカ★ナイトフィーバー
Luka Luka Night Fever!
私はここに居るから
I'll be right here,
少しでも視線を逸らしちゃ
so don't look away even for a second!
ダメダメよ
Don't you dare!
あ、すごい綺麗だった。
Ah, it was so pretty.
ギャオー！
Rawr!
可愛い可愛い！
So cute, so cute!
みんなの気持ちをね、こうやってね、ライブしてね。
Let's channel everyone's feelings into this live.
可愛い可愛い！
So cute, so cute!
僕はね、あれだから、うんうん、ころさんはやっぱ、うんうんってなってた。
I mean, Korone-san was all like, "Yeah, yeah."
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
保護者だね、もう。
You're like a guardian already!
そう、もうね、うんうん、さすがだね、わかってたけどね、みたいな。
Yeah, like, "Yep, yep, as expected," even though I knew it.
ありがとうね。
Thank you!
いや、今度の時間はね、えっと、この間のお披露目で、おかころってなかなかね、
Since we rarely stream together just the two of us,
2人で配信することないから。
like at the recent outfit reveal...
確かに。
True.
えっとね、ちょっと待って。
Um, hold on a second.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
今更ちょっと疲れがきた。
The fatigue is catching up with me now.
大丈夫だよ。
It's okay.
ぼくが代わりにね、この衣装で、まぁ2人で並ぶことってすごい珍しいので、
I'll take over—since it's so rare for us to match outfits,
今回は、えっと、少しの時間ね、おかころの写真撮影をしていこうかなと思います。
we're gonna take some Okakoro photos for a bit.
思います！やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
なんかね、コメント、ね、なんかどんなポーズが欲しいかとかね、いろいろね、
Also, in the comments, let us know what kind of poses you want...
そうだね、教えてもらいつつ教えてもらいつつ、それにちょっと答えていこうかなって感じ。
Yeah, while taking suggestions, we'll answer them as we go.
だからスクショタイムということで、みんなこの上のタグをさ、つけてさ、あの投稿してくれたら
So it's screenshot time! We'd be super happy if you post
すっごい嬉しいよ！
using the hashtag above!
嬉しいよ！ありがとう！
We'd be so happy! Thank you!
あ、カメラ！
Ah, camera!
カメラある、カメラある！
There's a camera, there's a camera!
わあ！わーわーわー！わーわーわー！
Yay! Wow, wow, wow!
いいねいいね、どんなポーズがいいかな？
Nice, nice. What kind of pose should we do?
ハートマークつける？ハートマーク。いいよ！
Put a heart mark? A heart mark. Sure!
じゃあ、こう手で作ろう、手で。いいよ。
Then let's make it with our hands, with our hands.
ハートじゃない！
That's not a heart!
あ、ごめんごめん、オッケーオッケー。
Ah, sorry sorry, okay okay.
ハートじゃ、ごめんごめんごめん！
A heart—wait, sorry sorry sorry!
もう！もう！
Jeez! Jeez!
すぐチュウするんだけど。
We always kiss right away.
いいでしょ？今日、今日泣きながら。
Isn't it fine? Today, crying today.
はっ、待って、これさ、大きいハートなら作れるんだよ。
Wait, we can make a big heart.
大きいハート。そう、いいでしょ？待って、スクウェアならいけそう。
A big heart. Yeah, right? Wait, a square might work.
できたいけた、スクウェア！
We did it, a square!
これじゃダメかな？どうだろう、でもみんな可愛いと言ってくれてるからね。
Is this no good? But everyone says it's cute.
え、お尻も撮ってもらおう。お尻も。
Let's have them take pictures of our butts too.
お尻撮ってもらおう。はいよ。
Let's have them take pictures of our butts. Sure.
しっぽ！アイドルしっぽです。
Tail! Idol tail.
ああ、アイドルしっぽです。
Ah, idol tail.
なんかおがゆのしっぽと並ぶと、でっかい犬のしっぽさ。
Compared to Okayu's tail, it's a huge dog tail.
いや、それが可愛いんだよ！リボンもいい、可愛くない？
No, that's what's cute! The ribbon is nice too, isn't it cute?
リッパじゃん、リッパ！
It's magnificent, magnificent!
ちょっとやそっとのことじゃちぎれないからね。
It won't tear easily over trifles.
確か、僕のすぐちぎれちゃうからさ、わけてあげるんだから。
True, mine tears off easily, so I'll share some with you.
いらない！いらない！
Don't want it! Don't want it!
取れたかなみんな、取れた？
Did you manage to capture it, everyone? Did you get it?
取れた？
Did you get it?
やっぱね、僕たちはしっぽが可愛いからね、しっぽがね。
After all, our tails are cute, the tails are.
なんかコメントでみんな、いいよ言って！いいで思っと、自分をさらけ出して。
Like, in the comments everyone, say it's good! Expose yourselves.
本当にレアだからね、みんな分かってる？これ。
It's really rare, so does everyone know this?
おかゆとのね、あのメモリーを残したいんだよ、これきっと。
I want to leave memories with Okayu, for sure.
メモリーよね？そう、だからみんな、なんか
Memories, right? So everyone, like...
抱き合ってくれだって。
They're saying hug each other.
ああ！抱き合ってるの。
Ah! Hugging.
そうだね、ぎゅあ、ぎゅー、ぎゅー、ぎゅー、ぎゅー。
That's right, hug, hug, hug, hug.
取れた？
Did you get it?
あ、ハイタッチしてだって。
Ah, they're saying do a high-five.
イエーーイ！
Yeeaah!
なんかこれ取れなくない？
Isn't this hard to capture?
確かに。みんな、スロー、スローモーションで。
True, everyone, in slow-motion.
スローモーションで。
In slow-motion.
イエーーイ！
Yeeaah!
取れた？
Did you get it?
これなら取れんじゃい？
If it's this, we can get it, right?
あ、楽しいな。
Ah, it's so fun.
ね、すごい楽しい！
Right, super fun!
ジャンプして、ジャンプして。
Jump, jump.
あ、1人だった。
Ah, I was alone.
2人で？2人でジャンプする？
Together? Jump together?
せーの、の、イエーーイ！
Ready, go, yeeaah!
でも、なんかハートもれちゃうこれ。
But a heart leaks out.
あ、だめだ、これだめだよ。
Ah, no good, this is no good.
だめだだめだ、ハートもれてしまうね。
No good, a heart leaks out.
初めてのさ、おかころ3Dコラボ覚えてる？
Remember our first Okakoro 3D collab?
え？
Eh?
フュージョンやったじゃん。
We did the fusion.
あ、やった！
Ah, we did!
やってもいいかな？
Can we do it?
フュージョン！イエーーイ！
Fusion! Yeeaah!
失敗した！
We failed!
あーあー、だめだ。
Ahh, no good.
失敗したわ。失敗した。失敗したわ。
We failed. We failed. We failed.
あ、しばきあげパンチングだって。やってて、カメラに近づいて。
Ah, beating-up punching. Do it close to the camera.
おらよ！
Take this!
そんな感じなの？
Is it like that?
普通になんかもっと。おらよ！
Normally, like... Take this!
で、プシーロール。うまいやんけ！
And pussy roll. You're good!
あ、観客も交えて撮影しない？
Ah, shouldn't we take photos including the audience?
そうやね。おにぎりと、おにぎりじゃ。
Ah, right. Rice ball and...
こっち、こっち、よくさ、こうやって、こうやりたい、これの。
Over here, often like this, I want to do this.
確かに。すごい、いいじゃん！
True. Wow, that's great!
あ、いいじゃん！
Ah, great!
はーーい！
Hiii!
いや、なんで最善取れなかった？マジで。
Seriously, why couldn't we get the best shot?
カメラマン、カモンカモン！カモンカモン！
Cameraman, come on! Come on!
最善跳ねよ！
Let's do the best jump!
確かに。ギリギリ前取れてない感じがね。
True, barely missing the front.
はーい！イエーーイ！
Hiii! Yeeaah!
いいぞぴーす！ピース！
Good job, peace! Peace!
どう？撮れた？みんな。
How was it? Did you get it, everyone?
いいぞ！いいじゃん！
Good! That's great!
ね、いいね。
Right, good.
可愛い
Cute!
いいね
Nice!
いいですね
That's nice.
どんな感じ？
How is it?
あ、ごめんよって
Ah, you said "sorry"?
最前取れなくてごめんよ謝っとる
Apologizing for not getting the front row.
だめだったんだね
It didn't work out, huh?
まあ確かに一番前取るのってめっちゃ難しいからね。
Well, true, getting the very front row is super hard.
確かに。
True.
ああ、なんか
Ah, somehow...
すごいさ、なんか緊張とさ、なんか踊った疲れとさ、
I'm so nervous, and tired from dancing...
ころさん2連続ね激しめのダンスだったからね、ちょっとね。
Korone had intense dances two songs in a row, so...
褒めてあげる。
I'll praise you.
ありがとう！あ、すごい！あー！
Thank you! Ah, amazing! Ahh!
あ、飛ばされていく
Ah, getting blown away!
飛ばされていっちゃった。楽しい！楽しい！
Got blown away! So fun! So fun!
楽しい！楽しい！楽しい！楽しい！楽しい！楽しい！
Fun, fun, fun, fun, fun, fun!
犬と猫のポーズとかやってみる？
Want to try dog and cat poses?
いいよ。
Sure.
じゃあ、犬のポーズってなんだ？
Then, what's a dog pose?
お散歩？猫は猫
A walk? Cats are cats—
あ、わんわんわん、お散歩、わんわんわん
Ah, woof woof woof, walk, woof woof woof!
ほら、いくよ！わんわんわん、こっちだよ！
Here we go! Woof woof woof, over here!
わあ、わあ！こっちだよ！こっちだよ！
Wow, wow! Over here! Over here!
緊張が、緊張で死ぬ！
I'm dying from nervousness!
大丈夫大丈夫！ありがとう！で、猫、猫のポーズ、猫のポーズ。
It's okay, it's okay! Thank you! Now, cat, cat pose, cat pose.
にゃんにゃんにゃん
Nya, nya, nya!
かわいいじゃん
So cute!
にゃんにゃん、一緒にやろ？
Nya nya, let's do it together?
今の何だったん？コーリーの
What was that just now, Korii's?
にゃんにゃんにゃん、にゃんにゃんにゃん
Nya nya nya, nya nya nya!
かわいいのアップでしょ？
A cute close-up, right?
にゃんにゃんにゃん、にゃんにゃんにゃん
Nya nya nya, nya nya nya!
ああ、かわいいってね。
Ah, so cute.
かわいいでしょ。
Cute, right?
さっきの何だったんだろ？
What was that just now?
あ、じゃあ、待って、Okayuも犬のポーズじゃん。
Ah, wait, Okayu is doing the dog pose too.
ええ、いざ使われると
Eh, when it actually gets used—
動けないよ、ほら、お散歩！
Can't move, look, walk!
この前もやったじゃん！
We did this the other day too!
おいで、おいで。
Come here, come here.
ええ、動けない。
Eh, can't move.
ほら動けない、動けない！
Look, can't move, can't move!
おいで！
Come here!
やだ！おいで、おいで、おいで！
No way! Come here, come here, come here!
リード長すぎだろ、これ！
Your leash is way too long for this!
やだ！おいで、おいで、おいで、やだ！
No way! Come here, come here, come here, no way!
だめだ、このね、このねこちゃんはだめだ、言うこと聞かない。
No good, this cat here, no good, won't listen.
そうだよ。
That's right.
ああ、だめだった。
Ah, no good.
直立不動じゃいけないんだ。
Can't just stand at attention.
ちちちち、くさー！ちちちちちち
Chi-chi-chi-chi, stinky! Chi-chi-chi-chi-chi-chi!
いやいや、いいですよ、男子よりこの今のこれですごい疲れたんだから。
No no, it's fine, we got so tired from this current thing more than boys.
本当に、リードでね、リードですごい疲れた。
Really, got so tired from the leash.
確かに、リードで疲れちゃいましたね。
True, we got tired from the leash.
何を見せられてるんだってコメント、あ、すみませんでした！
Comments asking "What are we being shown?", ah, I'm sorry!
面白くない。
Not funny.
あとは、なんかみんなある？なんか本当今日控えめだね、なんで？
Also, is there anything from everyone? Why are they so reserved today?
いや、みんなも緊張してるんじゃない？久しぶりのさ。おっかゆ！
Well, aren't they all nervous? It's been a while. Okayu!
おかもとライブで、ほら、ラム部し合って。
At Okayu's live, look, rubbing shoulders.
ソーラン、ソーラン
Soran, Soran!
高橋さん、高橋さん！
Takahashi-san, Takahashi-san!
ソーラン、ソーラン、ほい、ほい！
Soran, Soran, hoi, hoi!
やあ、やあ、ほい、ほい！
Ya, ya, hoi, hoi!
背中合わせやってだって。どういうこと？
They're doing back-to-back, they said. What does that mean?
かっこいい。
Cool.
うえーい、うえーい！あ、次の曲っぽくない？
Uei, uei! Ah, doesn't it feel like the next song?
あ、やった、やった、やってた！
Ah, they did it, they did it!
はあ。
Haa.
なに？ばれて、ばれて、曲っぽく。
What? Getting caught, getting caught, sounding like a song.
ばれてる、ばれてる！
Getting caught, getting caught!
なにそれ？ばれてない、ばれてない！
What is that? Not caught, not caught!
ネタバレ、ころさんだ。ネタバレ犬だ。
Spoilers, Korone. Spoiler dog.
あ、待って、じゃあ次の曲は何だと思う、みんな？
Ah, wait, then what do you all think the next song is?
予想？
Guess?
予想。
Guess.
これっぽいやつ。これっぽい。
Something like this. Looks like it.
あれ？できなくなった。
Huh? Can't do it anymore.
うえーい、いえーい！
Uei, iei!
なんだろう。
I wonder what it is.
あ、とか言ってるけどみんな分かってないからね、これ。そんなに当たってない。
Ah, saying that, but everyone doesn't know yet, right? Not hitting it that much.
当たってないよ、みんな。
You guys aren't hitting it.
そんなに当たってない。残念でした。
Not hitting it that much. Too bad.
ユーほど当たってない。
Not hitting it as much as You.
ええ、じゃあみんなも気になってるだろうしさ、そろそろ。
Eh, well, everyone must be curious, so soon.
ね、行ってみたいの？
Hey, want to go see?
行きますか？
Shall we go?
行きますか！
Let's go!
じゃあ、早速次の曲に、行きたいと、思います！
Then, let's go right into the next song!
せーの！
Ready, go!
るるるるるるるるるるるるる、ろき！
Rururururururururu... Roki!
さあ眠眠打破 昼夜逆転 VOX AC30W
So, wake up, day and night inverted, VOX AC30W
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイがバンド仲間にゃっほー
A subculture boy carrying a telecaster says hi to his bandmates
アルバイトはネクラモード
Part-time job is in gloomy mode
対バンにはATフィールド
AT field against rival bands
“人見知り”宣言で逃げる気か boy
Planning to run away with an "antisocial" declaration, boy?
ゆーてお坊っちゃんお嬢ちゃん お金も才能も
You say rich kids, money and talent too
なまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
Having them just halfway is troublesome
boys be ambitious... like this old man
長い前髪 君誰の信者 信者 信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you, follower, follower
勘違いすんなよ 教祖はオマエだ
Make no mistake, the cult leader is you!
さあ睡眠打破 昼夜逆転 VOX AC30W
Come on, sleep-depriving Dinki-Di, turn night to day, Vox AC30 watts on
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイがバンド仲間にやっほー
Telecaster-bearing subculture boy saying "yaho" to his bandmates
アルバイトはネコラモード
Part-time job in gloom mode
対バンドにはATフィールド
Against the band's AT field
“人見知り”宣言で逃げる気か boy
"I'm shy" declaration, thinking of running away, boy?
ゆーて お坊ちゃんお嬢ちゃん お金も才能も
Saying that, little master and young miss, money and talent
なまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
Having just enough is troublesome, you see
boys be ambitious…
Boys be ambitious...
like this old man
長い前髪
Long bangs,
君誰の信者
whose follower are you?
信者
Follower,
follower
勘違いすんな 教祖はオマエだ
Don't get it wrong, the cult leader is you
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll
かき鳴らす エレクトリックギターは
Strumming electric guitar, saying
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ 君の全てを 曝け出してみせろよ
Come on, show us everything you've got and expose it all
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll
さあ 日進月歩 いい曲書いてる？ 動員ふえてる？
Come on, day by day, writing good songs? Audience increasing?
「知名度あるけど 人気はそんなにないから 色々大変ですね。」
"You have some fame, but not much popularity, so it must be hard."
はっきり言うなよ 匿名アイコン
Don't say it so clearly, anonymous icon
はっきり見せない 実写のアイコン
Real life icon hiding your face
いい歳こいて 自意識まだ boy
Good age and still self-conscious, boy?
ぶっちゃけどんだけ 賢くあざとくやったって
To be honest, no matter how smartly and cunningly you do it
10年後に メイクは落ちてんだよ
10 years from now, the makeup will wash off
boys be ambitious…
Boys be ambitious...
like this old man
生き抜くためだ キメろ take a "selfy"
To survive, strike a pose, take a "selfy"
"selfy" "selfy"
死くんじゃねえぞ お互いにさっ！
Don't you dare die on me, we're in this together!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll
うっせえラブソングでもいいだ
Even a shallow love song is fine
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ目の前のあの子を 撃ち抜いてみせろよ
Come on, shoot down the girl right in front of you and show us
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
Can't be satisfied by beating around the bush
スタジオに運ばれたスロートコートは
Throat coat carried into the studio
安心 不安気 プレッシャーでいっぱい
Filled with relief, anxiety, and pressure
「実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません」
"Actually, I've had a cold since yesterday and can't use my voice"
はっ？はっ？はっ？はっ？
Ha? Ha? Ha? Ha?
はぁ… 寝言は寝て言え
Ha... Talk in your sleep, baby
ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー
Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby
死くんじゃねえぞ お互いにさっ！
Don't you dare die on me, we're in this together!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll
かき鳴らす エレクトリックギターは
Strumming electric guitar, saying
don't stop! don't stop!
さあ 君の全てを さあ曝け出してみせろよ
Come on, show us everything you've got and expose it all
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki Rock 'n' Rock 'n' Roll
死くんじゃねえぞ（死くんじゃねえぞ）
Don't you dare die (Don't you dare die)
死にたかねえのは お互い様！
Neither of us wants to die!
はー！いや踊ったよー！
Haa! Man, we danced so much!
ロキ！
Roki!
いやもうね、ぴょんぴょん！ぴょん跳びすぎたね！
Man, we were jumping up and down! Jumped way too much!
あと皆もポチポチありがとう！
And thanks everyone for tapping along!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
ちょっと激しめだったね。
That was pretty intense.
いや本当に！だったね！
Yeah, truly! It was!
え、どうだったコロネさんはさ、ロキを踊ってみて、ここちょっと注目してほしいなみたいなさ。
So, Korone-san, how was it dancing to Roki? Tell us your thoughts.
注目か、あでもね、
Attention, huh? Well,
なんか、こう立ち位置が変わる時あったじゃん？
there were times when our positions changed, right?
ああ、入れ替わる時ね。
Ah, when we swapped places.
あれすごいさ、なんか本当コンビって感じでよかったと思わん？
That was amazing, don't you think it really felt like a duo?
みんなちょっと、あと、あれがあったじゃん？
Everyone... and also, there was that, right?
私ね、あの受け身取ったりするの超うまいから。
Me, I'm super good at taking falls and stuff.
うまいよね。
You are good.
あの安心して殴れる
Like, you can punch safely—
のま、殴られ慣れてるみたいなさ。
You're so used to getting punched.
気持ちよかった！気持ちよかった！
It felt great! It felt great!
ちょっと問題発言ですけどそれ。大丈夫だった？
That's a bit of a problematic statement. Was that okay?
大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's fine, it's fine, it's fine.
なでなでして？
Pat my head?
よちよち。
There, there.
いたーい！
Ouch!
なんでだよ！帰り際だなこれ、何も触れずに帰ろうや。
Why'd you do that?! Let's just leave without mentioning anything.
わしわしわし。
Pat pat pat.
みんな、みんな、ありがとうね。ありがと、よかったよ。
Everyone, thank you so much. Thank you, it was great.
もう草しかない、草しかない。
It's all "lol"s now, pure "lol"s.
えもうさ、ぶっちゃけね、ちょっと話変わっちゃうけど、
Also, honestly, changing the subject a bit,
まぁここでさ、まぁ今まで2周年あっという間にいろんなことあったけどさ、どうだったコロネさん？
up until now for our 2nd anniversary, so many things happened, how was it, Korone-san?
いやでもやっぱりさ、なんだろう...
Well, but still, I wonder...
のあさん、
Korone-san,
いやもさん、本当エイプリルフールに発表だったじゃん。
it was actually announced on April Fools', right?
やっぱみんながさ、いや嘘だぁ、みたいな。
Like, everyone was like, "No way, you're joking."
うそなんだよ、本当なんだよ、どっち？みたいな。
Is it a lie? Is it real? Which is it?
まぁ確かにそう、流れだったじゃん。なんかちょっとデビューしづらかったよね？
Well, true, that's how it went. It must have been a bit hard to debut, right?
まぁ確かに。でもうちはもうにやにやしてたけど。
Well, true. But I was just grinning the whole time.
本当に。好きなのね、そういうのね。ちっちっち、本当なんだよなって。
Seriously. You love that kind of stuff. "Chil-chil, it's true."
ね。でもさ、えっと、おかころがデビューしてさ、ね、結構本当いま仲間がいっぱい増えたじゃんか。
Right. But after we debuted, our friends really grew a lot, right?
僕たちがさ、その今ね、たくさんいるけどメンバー、その中
Even though there are so many members now, among them—
が、で、多分真ん中あたりが、ちょうど僕たちみたいな感じなんだよね。
Right, and the middle part is probably just like us.
確かにそこだね。いまいっぱい仲間がいて、本当にね、あの、いっぱい
That's true. There are so many friends now, really, you know, so many...
え、いっぱいになったよね。
Yeah, our numbers have grown.
本当だね。本当に、ありがとう。
That's right. Thank you so much.
本当みんなのおかげだよ、応援してくれるみんながいるから。
It's all thanks to everyone, because we have everyone cheering us on.
もちろん、いっぱいあの、僕たちも楽しんで活動ができます。本当にありがとうございます。
Of course, we get to enjoy our activities so much too. Thank you truly.
そうだね、ありがとう。
That's right, thank you.
嬉しいね。しかもね、やっぱ僕たち途中からゲーマーズに2人でこう入るってなったんだけど、
I'm so happy. And you know, we ended up joining Gamers together halfway through,
ま、そんときに、ま、ころさんにね、僕からそのホロライブ一緒に這入ろうよって、面白そうだから這入ろうよって。
and back then, I asked Korone, "Hey, let's join Hololive together," because it looked fun.
え、そう、おかゆがね、声かけてくれて、こーねはちょっと、お、どうやってみようかな、みたいな。
Yeah, Okayu reached out to me, and I was like, "Hmm, should I try it?"
そうそうそう。それであの、こうやって今なんだかんだ2周年を迎えられてっていうのが、僕はすごくね、ありがたくも嬉しいようなそんな気がしているんだよね。
Right, right. And now, somehow we've reached our 2nd anniversary, and I feel so grateful and happy about it.
来年も一緒にこうやってね、お互い並んで、3周年もね、
I hope we can stand side by side like this next year and celebrate our 3rd anniversary too.
迎えたいと思いますので。
celebrate our 3rd anniversary too.
そうだね、ずっと一緒にいたいね。
That's right, I want to stay together forever.
ね、おかゆとも一緒にいっぱいいたいし、みんなともね、もちろんずっと一緒にいたいので、ね。
Yeah, I want to spend lots of time with Okayu, and of course with everyone else forever too.
そうだね。新しくね、ここでね、くるって回転してね、あれ、観客を映したらすごいエモいこと、あ！
That's right. And now, if we spin around right here... wait, if we show the audience, it's so emotional—ah!
どうもどうも！
Hello, hello!
え、ちょっと、いいんじゃないんだ、ね！ありがとうみんな！ありがとう！
Ah, wait, isn't this nice, right? Thank you everyone! Thank you!
いい感じだ、いま。
That was a nice vibe just now.
そうだね、ちょっとエモ、エモ、エモチックパートでしたね。
Yeah, that was an emotional, emotional part.
よかった。ねえ、まあ、これでね、今回のライブは、この歌がね、次の歌が、最後に、なっちゃうんです、よ。
I'm glad. And you know, this live... this song, the next song is going to be the last one.
やだー！
No way!
やだね！やだ！やだ！
No way! No! No!
やだけど、やだやだ。だってちょっと早すぎないか？ちょっと待ってよ、やだやだ！
No, but no way. Isn't this too fast? Wait a minute, no way!
もっと、え、あと1時間2時間、オッケーですって言ってるよ。オッケーですって言ってるよ。
More—wait, it says another 1 or 2 hours is okay! It says it's okay!
じゃあ、こうじれですか？あ、そうですって言ってるよ。
Is that so? Ah, it says yes!
もう、それを鵜呑みにして大人になっちゃダメなんだよ。
You mustn't just take that at face value and grow up.
あ、そういう勉強をえていうことで今日は、そうだよ、はいっていうのはこういうことなんだよ。わかった。
Ah, we're learning about that today—yes, that's what "yes" means. Understood.
えーと、寂しい、みんなも寂しいよね？
Um, I'm lonely, everyone's lonely too, right?
うん、私も、寂しいんだよ、本当は。
Yeah, I'm actually lonely too.
本当に？そう、いま強い子だ。
Really? Yeah, being a strong girl right now.
あ、エモい、エモい。
Ah, so emotional, so emotional.
あ、もう、待って、もうスクショいらん、大丈夫みんな！大丈夫？時間ちょっとあるで？
Ah, wait, no more screenshots needed, is everyone okay? Are you okay? We still have a bit of time, right?
カメラマンさん、カメラマンさん、え、おかゆ。わー！
Cameraman, cameraman, hey, Okayu. Whoa!
え、じゃあ、1、2分ちょっとさ、まあまたスクショタイムで最後バイバイしたいよ。え、はやい、1時間って早いよ！なんでこんな早いんだろう、ねえ！早いよね！
Um, well, for 1 or 2 minutes, let's have a screenshot time and say bye at the end. Eh, fast! An hour goes by so fast! Why is it so fast, hey! It's so fast, right?
鉄の、鉄の、ってやつです。鉄なしだよ。
That's the "no iron" thing. No iron.
ねえ、早いんだよ、時間って。
Yeah, it's fast, time is.
なに？運転してほしい、いいよ。おー。え、だってこーねが運転して迎えに来るからさ、野良だぜ。
What? I want you to drive, sure. Whoa. Well, because Korone will drive and come pick me up, like a stray.
野良だ。おーい。あ、ころさん。やっほー。乗っていいな？いいよ。
A stray. Hey. Ah, Korone-san. Yahoo. Can I get on? Sure.
楽しいこれ？え、これ楽しい？楽しかった？いや、私たちは楽しいけどね。楽しくない？大丈夫？
Is this fun? Eh, is this fun? Was it fun? Well, we're having fun. Not fun? Are you okay?
バイクもいい、バイクだ！あ、バイクいいよ、いいよ、いいよ。あ、じゃあまた迎えに来てもらうか。いいよ。
Bikes are good too, a bike! Ah, bikes are good, good, good. Ah, then come pick me up again later. Sure.
おら、ヘルメット。あ。楽しいのこれ？全然楽しくないよね！
Helmet. Ah. Is this fun? Not fun at all!
やっちまった。ちょっとシュールな。シュールなね。やばいな。
I messed up. Kinda surreal. Surreal, huh. This is bad.
笑いを提供してしまいましたけれども。じゃあ踊る？そうだよ。
We provided some laughs though. Then shall we dance? That's right.
踊らないとだよ。おかゆどう、次の曲。次の曲は、ポイントは、僕ところさんは、もしかしたら別の動きをするかもしれない。
We have to dance. Okayu, how about the next song? The next song's point is... Korone and I might do different movements.
え？そうなの？そう。そんな気がしてならないんだよね。本当？本当？なんかそんな気がするんだよね。わかった。
Eh? Is that so? Yeah. I can't help feeling that way. Really? Really? I kind of feel that way. Understood.
じゃあ頑張って歌って踊るからね。おどるー！がんばってさ、みんな本当に、あのね、すーんって終わるから、たぶん。
Then we'll do our best to sing and dance. Let's dance! Everyone, do your best, truly, you know, it'll just end in a flash, probably.
たぶんすーんって終わるから、あの、みんな本当に今日来てくれてありがとうねって言っとく。ありがとー！
It'll probably end in a flash, so I'll just say thank you so much everyone for coming today. Thank you!
おにぎりゃさんも、ほらねすきよ、おにぎりゃ、ありがとー！
Onigirya-san too, hey, we love you, Onigirya, thank you!
本当にありがとう！じゃあ、次いきますか。
Thank you so much! Well then, shall we go to the next one?
頑張って歌います。おかころ2周年、本当に、本当に、ありがとー！がんばるぞー！
We'll sing our best. Okakoro 2nd anniversary, truly, truly, thank you! Let's do our best!
では、最後の曲、聞いてください。「チルノのパーフェクトさんすう教室」！
Now, please listen to the final song: "Cirno's Perfect Math Class"!
(みんなー! チルノのさんすう教室はじまるよー!),s:
Everyone! Cirno's arithmetic class is starting!
(あたいみたいな天才目指して、がんばっていってね!),s:
Aim to be a genius like me and do your best!
キラキラ ダイヤモンド 輝く星のように,s:
Sparkling diamond like a shining star,
栄光 志望校 なんとかして入ろう,s:
Glory and prestige school, let's enter somehow!
天才 秀才 トップ目指して GO GO!!,s:
Genius, talent, top goal, GO GO!!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
ちょ、ちがっ、バカじゃないもん!,s:
Who's the baka, you're not a baka!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
バカっていうほうがバカなのよ!,s:
Those who call others baka are the baka!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
なによ、うるさいわね!このバカ!,s:
Why are you so noisy, you baka!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
紅魔館から バスが出て 初めに三人乗りまして,s:
A bus leaves Scarlet Devil Mansion, three people got on first,
白玉霊で一人降りて 半人だけ乗りまして,s:
One person got off at Hakugreak, and half a person got on.
八雲さんちで二人降りて 結局乗客合計何人だ?,s:
Two people got off at Yuyuko's place, so how many passengers are there in total?
答えは答えは ゼロ人ゼロ人,s:
The answer is zero people, zero people!
なぜならなぜなら それは 幻想郷にバス無い,s:
Why, why, because there are no buses in Gensokyo!
山落ち意味などないわ キャラクター立てればいいのよ,s:
Falling off mountains makes no sense, you gotta make characters stand out!
元気があればなんでも 1・2・9!,s:
If you have energy, anything goes! 1, 2, 9!
くるくる時計の針 ぐるぐる頭回る,s:
Spinning clock hands, spinning head around,
だってつぶら目玉 二つしかないのに,s:
Even though there are only two eyeballs to smash,
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかんかん,s:
Three clock hands? Chinpunkankan!
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く,s:
Next question coming up, the lesson still continues.
凍る部屋の中 ひんやりした温度も時間も気にせず ゆっくりしていってね!,s:
In a freezing room, don't worry about the chilly temperature or time, take it easy!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ!,s:
That's why I'm saying I'm not a baka!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
いい加減にしなさい これどうするのよ そしてコラボだなんて死ねばいいのよ,s:
Make it al dente, freeze-dry it, and then become a collaborator and die!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
永遠亭の 100万円の 壺を誰か壊しちゃった,s:
Someone messed up with a 1 million yen vase at Eientei,
永遠亭の エーリンが 弁償しに来ましたよ,s:
Reisen and Eirin came to the mansion to demand compensation.
白銀の幾つらねい 結局場所代幾ら?,s:
White silver of several jars, how much is the replacement cost in total?
答えは答えは ゼロ人ゼロ人,s:
The answer is zero people, zero people!
それはそんな壺あるわけない 常識超えたところに 世界の真理はある,s:
There's no way a vase like that exists, world truth lies beyond common sense!
秘密の数珠 目指して 1・2・9!,s:
Aim for the mysterious numbers 1, 2, 9!
ヘラヘラ ニヤケながら ケラケラ 笑いながら,s:
Sulkily smirking, grinning and laughing,
うさぎはうさぎ 可愛いでもないのに,s:
Rabbits are rabbits, even though they aren't cute.
真夏のチュータマンは ほいほいほい,s:
Midsummer's tutor man is hot, hot, hot!
大声 100万回に 漏れなく組様なして 調子のることなのよ どっちが良くなるならさ,s:
With 1 million loud voices, missing no members, if one gets better,
ばかんべものお疲れ様って言っとこうね わかった!,s:
It's like telling an idiot "good job", I get it!
頭が割に も天才だから 嫉妬してるでしょ,s:
My head is split, but I'm a genius, so you must be jealous, right?
本当しかたないわね あたいの天才の秘訣を ちょっとだけ教えてあげてもいいわよ,s:
It can't be helped, I'll teach you a little bit of my genius secret!
Hを 集めて集めて集めて集め束ねても,s:
Gathering H, gathering, gathering, gathering and collecting,
あたいのあたいのあたいのあたいのあたいの冷えちゃう,s:
My head, my head, my head, my head, my head gets cold!
頭に頭に頭に頭に叶わない,s:
Head, head, head, head, it won't yield!
ラムシャムシャムシャムシャムシャムシャムシャムシャムシャムシャムシャ,s:
Ram-sam-sam-sam-sam-sam-sam-sam-sam-sam-sam-sam!
止めれば 憧れの グングン 手をひねる,s:
Stop it, yearn for gung-ho, twist your hands!
あたいはあたいあたいあたいあたいあたいあたい完璧 ゆるいゆるいゆるいゆるいパーフェクト,s:
My head is, my head is, my head is, my head is, my head is perfect, loose, loose, loose, loose, perfect!
100億兆万パーフェクトリー!,s:
100 billion trillion percent perfect ree!
くるくる時計の針 ぐるぐる頭回る,s:
Spinning clock hands, spinning head around,
だってつぶら目玉 二つしかないのに,s:
Even though there are only two eyeballs to smash,
三本の針なんて ちんぷんかんかん,s:
Three clock hands? Chinpunkankan!
次々問題出る まだまだ授業続く,s:
Next question coming up, the lesson still continues.
凍る部屋の中 ひんやりした温度も時間も気にせず ゆっくりしていってね!,s:
In a freezing room, don't worry about the chilly temperature or time, take it easy!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ!,s:
That's why I'm saying I'm not a baka!
(バカバカバカ バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Baka baka baka...
いい加減にしなさい これどうするのよ そしてコラボだなんて死ねばいいのよ (バカバカバカ バカバカバカ),s:
Make it a bit more moderate, or I don't care, Baka baka baka...
だからバカじゃないって言ってるでしょ!,s:
That's why I'm saying I'm not a baka!
100億兆万パーフェクトリー!,s:
100 billion trillion percent!
おかころ 2周年 LIVE
[Okakoro 2nd Anniversary LIVE]